And her first class is "Intergalactic Revolutionaries and You," and America is so excited, she's ready to show off her strength, she's ready to show off her portal-punching skills, (Laughter) and I stripped that safety net from her right away. And I limited her powers, and I changed up her location and shook up her world, because that is what college is like, (Laughter) especially if you're alone. But I didn't want America to be alone for long, and so in a homework assignment gone totally wrong, she lands on a battlefield with the X-Men. (Laughter) Because, when I was in college, the Reverend Kelly Brown Douglas was my mentor, and I knew that America Chavez needed one, too. And who better to mentor America Chavez than Storm, the first black female superhero and one of the most powerful members of the X-Men? Nobody, that's who. (Laughter) And Storm teaches America how to quiet her mind inside of a star portal, and when America quiets her mind, she opens up the dimensions, and in that silence, she can listen for anything and anyone. And no one has ever offered her silence and deep reflection as a way to be powerful. And at first, she rejects it, but with Storm's encouragement, it clicks, and America quiets the world around her, and she leans into a deep vulnerability. I mean, her and Storm even hug. I know. And that's because my mentors loved me enough to encourage me to investigate myself and my ancestors, and when you're 19, how do you even know what that means? I didn't learn about the history of my people in college. I learned about the history of my people sitting on my grandmother's lap when she pulled out the photo album and she named everyone that was here and everyone still left on the island. So obviously, I had to crash-land a grandma on America Chavez, and not just any grandma -- a big, strong, luchador grandma, one that loved her enough to take her to the ancestral plain, where America Chavez could see the history of her people play out in the skies above. And America gets to see Planeta Fuertona, the birth planet of her grandmother, and she sees it get invaded, and she sees her grandmother and her mom flee. And she also sees the joy that they experience when their new homeland accepts them openly and offers them tremendous care. She gets to see great pain met with even greater compassion, and that's right alongside the tremendous strength of her family. And so everywhere that I could, right, I wrote her little love notes for her and for all the other queer kids of color trying to be magnificent. Like, when you lose yourself, dig deep into your ancestry, because you will find the pieces there. And also, reminders that soft is not a pass to duck, to hide, to be silent, to cower. Soft is also a push to hold ourselves accountable. Kind of like when America lands in World War II and comes face-to-face with Hitler, and she knocks him the hell out ... (Laughter) just like Captain America did in 1941, and who knew we'd need America Chavez to punch Nazis in 2018. (Laughter) (Applause) And even that, that justified act kind of wrecks her a little bit, so I made sure that she linked up with her best friend, and they talk feelings and they go on a road trip and they sing "Just a Girl" by No Doubt at the top of their lungs. (Laughter) And when Midas, a sinister corporation, takes control of Sotomayor, threatens to ban portals and almost kills America ... her ancestors reach for her ... because they know that she needs to heal. And it is that burst of care, that healing, that gives her the fuel to defeat Midas and reclaim herself. See, because that myth of having to go it alone and having to be tough ... doesn't serve us. America Chavez is a whole superhero, and she still needed a team of support to help her find herself. And she needed that gentleness, the type of gentleness that is rooted in compassion and still very much invested in justice and liberation. Because it's in that space where softness and vulnerability meet strength that we transcend our everyday selves, that we become something greater, something majestic, maybe even something super. Thank you. (Applause)
Son premier cours est « Révolutions intergalactiques et vous » et America est si impatiente, elle est prête à montrer sa force, à exhiber ses compétences d'ouverture de portails au poing (Rires) et je lui ai immédiatement ôté ce filet de sécurité. J'ai limité ses pouvoirs, j'ai changé sa position et bouleversé son monde parce que c'est ça l'université. (Rires) Surtout si vous êtes seul. Mais je ne voulais pas qu'America soit trop longtemps seule alors, durant un devoir ayant mal tourné, elle atterrit sur le champ de bataille avec les X-Men. (Rires) Car, quand j'étais à l'université, le révérend Kelly Brown Douglas était mon mentor et je savais qu'America Chavez avait aussi besoin d'un mentor. Qui de mieux placé que Tornade pour être la mentore d'America Chavez, la première super-héroïne noire et l'un des membres les plus puissants des X-Men ? Personne. (Rires) Tornade enseigne à America comment apaiser son esprit dans un portail galactique et quand America apaise son esprit, elle ouvre les dimensions et, dans ce silence, elle peut écouter tout et tout le monde. Personne ne lui a jamais offert le silence et la réflexion profonde en tant que façon d'être forte. Au début, elle rejette cela mais avec les encouragements de Tornade, le déclic arrive, America calme le monde qui l'entoure et s'avance vers une profonde vulnérabilité. Tornade et elle se font même un câlin, je sais. C'est parce que mes mentors m'ont assez aimée pour m'encourager à m'explorer, moi et mes ancêtres, et quand vous avez 19 ans, comment savoir ce que cela signifie ? Je n'ai pas appris l'histoire des miens à l'université. J'ai appris l'histoire des miens assise sur les genoux de ma grand-mère quand elle a sorti l'album photo et qu'elle a nommé tous ceux qui étaient là et ceux restés sur l'île. Évidemment, une grand-mère devait atterrir d'urgence dans la vie d'America Chavez et pas n'importe quelle grand-mère -- une grand-mère grande, forte, une battante qui l'aimait assez pour l'amener dans le plan ancestral, où America Chavez pourrait voir l'histoire des siens se dérouler dans les cieux. America voit la planète Fuertona, la planète natale de sa grand-mère, la voit être envahie et voit sa grand-mère et sa mère fuir. Elle voit également la joie qu'elles éprouvent quand leur nouvelle patrie les accepte ouvertement et s'occupe très bien d'elles. Elle voit l'immense douleur à laquelle répond une compassion plus grande encore et cela existe aux côtés de l'immense force de sa famille. Partout où je le pouvais, je lui ai écrit des mots doux pour elle et pour tous les autres enfants homosexuels de couleur essayant d'être formidables. Quand vous vous perdez, plongez dans votre ascendance car vous y trouverez les morceaux. Cela vous rappellera également que la tendresse n'est pas l'autorisation d'esquiver, de se cacher, de se taire, de battre en retraire. La tendresse vous pousse aussi à vous tenir pour responsable. Comme quand America atterrit durant la seconde guerre mondiale, se retrouve face-à-face avec Hitler et l'assomme... (Rires) comme l'a fait Captain America en 1941. Qui aurait cru que nous aurions besoin qu'America Chavez frappe des Nazis en 2018. (Rires) (Applaudissements) Et même cela, cet acte justifié la dévaste un peu alors je me suis assurée qu'elle contacte sa meilleure amie, qu'elles parlent sentiments, partent faire une virée en voiture et chantent à tue-tête « Just a Girl » de No Doubt. (Rires) Quand Midas, une sinistre entreprise, prend le contrôle de Sotomayor, menace d'interdire les portails et va presque jusqu'à tuer America... ses ancêtres entrent en contact avec elle car elles savent qu'elle a besoin de guérir. Et c'est cet élan d'attention, cette guérison qui lui donne la force de vaincre Midas et de redevenir elle-même. Car ce mythe selon lequel il faut agir seul et être dur à cuire ne nous rend pas service. America Chavez est une super-héroïne entière et a quand même eu besoin d'une équipe pour la soutenir et l'aider à se trouver. Elle a eu besoin de cette douceur, le genre de douceur prenant racine dans la compassion et restant engagée pour la justice et la libération. Car c'est dans cet espace où la douceur et la vulnérabilité rencontrent la force que l'on transcende son soi ordinaire, que l'on devient quelque chose de plus grand, de majestueux, peut-être même de super. Merci. (Applaudissements)